<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>mila grigoryeva - misc</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00+03:00</updated><entry><title>Pair Programming</title><link href="/pair-programming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>mila</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-07-27:/pair-programming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I tried pair programming for the first time and it was pretty exciting! I've been a part of this one Slack community and one of the channels there matches you with a random community members once a month. 
So when I got a new match I offered to try …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I tried pair programming for the first time and it was pretty exciting! I've been a part of this one Slack community and one of the channels there matches you with a random community members once a month. 
So when I got a new match I offered to try out pair programming. From what I've heard before, pair programming is practiced in some companies, but I've never had a chance to try it. So this was more of an informal and fun way to do it. 
My match was an electrical engineer from Tampere who was interested in programming and has been taking some courses on the side (which is so impressive, she is a total grownup with kids and everything, so it's always impressive that those people have time to study).
She had less experience than me, but was familiar with Python, so we decided to code a Pomodoro timer using Tkinter, a Python binding to a Tk GUI toolkit. 
The whole point of this pair programming session was definitely not the complexity of the code we would produce, but the process of pair programming itself. Before starting our session, I quickly googled about the concept and found some nice materials. This one was my favorite: 
It is a pretty extensive guide, but provides a lot of useful points that I haven't even thought of. One of my concerns was our skill level gap, and I wanted to make sure I don't take over the whole session and give another person a chance to code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session went pretty well overall. We had quite a few technical issues, and since we weren't physically in one room it was a bit difficult to troubleshoot. We used VScode's Live Share extension, which is actually quite amazing. You can simultaneously edit files and even share servers and terminals. It also comes with an audio plugin, so you don't even need to use anything else besides VScode.
As I already mentioned, I tried not to overtake the whole process which is hard if you have more experience than the other person. I also tried to make sure that I don't assume that the other person didn't know something, but at the same time I didn't want to explain very basic things and come off as patronizing. But regardless of all these little things that I had to think about, I think the session went well and we managed to build the Pomodoro timer together. The code is very simple and it many other features can be added to improve the (desktop) app, but as I said, the whole point was to try out pair programming. My match told me she learned a lot, and that's what matters most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, I would like to be the less experienced person in the pair, so I could experience this from another perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>First Post on my new blog</title><link href="/first-post-on-my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-05T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2020-07-05T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>mila</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-07-05:/first-post-on-my-new-blog.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my new blog. It's built using Pelican, a static site generator that uses Python. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>